Hello friends, welcome to the
Technical Mom YouTube channel. Friends, today
we will talk about new bike insurance.
Like, when you go to the showroom
and buy a new bike, you get a
five-year insurance, in which 1 year is
first party, the remaining four years are
third party, that is, 4 years are
third party, but you want that
too to be your first party for 4 years, then
today in this video we
will talk about it in full detail, so stay tuned to this video
till the end, from which company should you do the
insurance? If you run a shop,
if you are a shopkeeper yourself, you
want to do it yourself, then you can do the same facility yourself, no
problem will be created, so
please subscribe to this channel
so that you keep getting videos related to it in future as well, so
let us
tell you in detail how you have to do the first
party in the second year,
so right now the trick I am telling you is
through CSC, you
can either go to the CSC center or you can do it yourself,
whatever amount you pay yourself,
you have to pay that amount at the CSC center also
So, one benefit you will get in this amount is
that you will also get a printout
or if you charge for the CC
then that is the normal charge, up to ₹50
is charged separately and you
also get a printout, there is no problem, there is
no problem with debit or credit card also, you
can get all these things from there only, but
how do you do first party insurance in the second year, it is
absolutely normal payment,
which is your third year third party insurance,
you just have to take insurance of the first party, so let's take it simply,
after going to Google Chrome browser, you simply have to search
CSC Logon,
as soon as you search CSC Logon,
you will get a page like this, you have to
click on Digital Seva Portal,
as soon as you click on Digital Seva Portal,
you will get a page like this, go
down and click on Logon, I am
telling you this from the phone so
that you can see everything on your phone or laptop, the
CSC portal should open like this
So what you have to do is simply
check here whether your phone is
in desktop mode or not. If you use desktop
mode then it will be very easy for you to
understand because your display will start
blinking just like a laptop or computer.
So let's click on desktop mode. As soon as you
click on desktop mode, a page will appear like this. So
simply you don't have to do anything, go
here and
click on insurance.
As soon as you click on insurance, I am
highlighting it and showing it to you. Here you will
scroll down and
here you will get the option of motor third
party. You have to
click on motor third party. I am
highlighting it and showing it to you.
As soon as you click on motor third party,
as I am highlighting it to you, you will
see here it is written
motor third party. You have to click on it. As
soon as you click on it, you will
find many companies, but
in this video I will
tell you through ICICI Lombard how to create it.
You have to click on search.
Here you will get two options. In one
you will see the option of click here and in the
other  If the clicker option is not visible
then what you have to do is simply
click on the click here option which is visible
and here if you want you
can also favorite it, it will start
showing to you without searching, so in this way
whatever you are seeing here, we
hope that you have understood everything properly till here,
now click on click here, as soon as you click on click here, the
next page will open and as soon as that page opens,
you will see some details here,
look at it on the side,
you will definitely have a portal, here you are
getting options of product, in
that two wheeler, PVC, GCB, health,
pay close attention to all these options, you have to make a two wheeler, if you want to
make a two wheeler third party then you
click on this option but you have to
make it first party because the third
party is yours, you have bought a new bike,
whether it is from any company, if it was
given to you by the agency people then there is no problem with that, if the
insurance of any company is given to you by the company then
you have no problem with that, let us
come down here and click on injury  We will do that, the
options you see here,
we will click on the scooter of cute, the
data will wait, now wait for a little while, the
portal is opening and as soon as it opens,
you have to pay attention
here, like you have to take only on
damage,
like when you go to this page now, you have to take it for new
bike, that too on it the third party
is already done, you have to take only Audi, if you want to take
on damage then here some
highlights are being shown to you, back to stand and
deep please click your back old side, as if
some update has happened on the side, then here it is saying
back old side, here you are
getting an option back to old side,
you have to click on it, as soon as you
click on it, you will go to back to old side
and from here you will get all those features,
what you have to do here is you have to enter the
numbers and click on get audio details,
like when you click on get RTO digital, the
details will appear and pay attention here, whether
you can take it from here or not, it does
not matter because that party would already be
covered.  And you have to
click on Get from here, for example, if
you enter any numbers here, please pay attention to one thing
here, I have fixed all the details,
you have to
look at all this carefully, so let me give you,
for example, I will enter the bike number
and show you the gift code,
I have entered the bike number and clicked on Get RTO
details, please it is waiting,
give me some time,
as you can see here, all the
details can be done automatically,
after selecting all these things, if you click on Gift here, then
your amount will be shown immediately, there are
some problems here, I have
given the picture not greater, registry, you can
see the date etc. here and you
can check it again, so
as we checked the number, there were some
problems in it, I
entered the number of another bike, as we have
entered the number etc. here, the value etc. has been
created automatically